<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>research | Umutcan Simsek</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tag/research/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tag/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>research</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 17:35:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>research</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tag/research/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>DiALSWS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/dialsws/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 17:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/dialsws/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The concept of &amp;ldquo;browsing the web&amp;rdquo; is being replaced by automated agents that access to structured content. Dialogue systems are a natural way to interact with the machine readable data and services on the web. With DIALSWS, we will develop an approach for annotating web APIs with a lightweight semantic vocabulary based on schema.org and an approach for semi-automatically generating open and flexible goal-oriented dialogue systems based on those Web APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schema.org is one of the biggest collaborative vocabulary engineering projects and for the time being the de-facto standart. We aim to leverage the high-level adoption of the vocabulary by web content publishers an give them guidelines and tools to annotate not only their data but also their Web APIs. The semantic description of Web APIs, then will be used for semi-automated generation of intelligent agents, particularly dialogue systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentation below introduces the Unified Intent Modeling Ontology (UIMO) with some examples. For the details of Web API annotation with schema.org actions, see the WASA Specification.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WASA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/wasa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 17:35:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/wasa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The schema.org vocabulary is a de facto industrial standard for creating semantically annotated data. The vocabulary with its actions subset that allows to describe not only entities on the web, but also actions that can be taken on them. The Web Service Annotation with Schema.org (WASA) language puts schema.org actions into a Web API perspective by restricting and extending it with the help of the domain specification process for the creation of WASA APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WASA language sees Web APIs as a collection of actions that can be taken on a graph resources. These actions can be linked explicitly, allowing clients to achieve certain goals without hardcoding the orchestration of these actions (i.e. order of action invocation). As a domain model to describe input and output parameters, we use domain-specific patterns that restrict and extend the schema.org vocabulary. An API publisher can define constraints over the input and output of an action via these pattern that are defined with SHACL shapes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DACH-KG</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/dach-kg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 09:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/dach-kg/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
